JESSIE BOUDREAU

POWER & ENERGY ENGINEER

226-581-0214



Jessie.boudreau@live.ca



/in/jessie-boudreau-46203ba5



www.jessieboudreau.com



Hamilton, ON L8L1W9



EDUCATION

BACHELOR OF TECHNOLOGY - POWER & ENERGY

McMaster University, Hamilton, Ontario 2017-2020

ADVANCED DIPLOMA – ENERGY SYSTEMS ENGINEERING TECHNOLOGY

Conestoga College ITAL, Cambridge, Ontario 2013-2017

ACHIEVEMENTS

MASTERCRAFT AWARD

Conestoga College, 2017

Awarded for the best overall engineering capstone project.

INTERESTS

- Rock Climbing
- Martial Arts
- Camping & Hiking
- Reading
- Hacking

PROFESSIONAL PROFILE

Experienced Engineering Team Manager with a demonstrated history of working in the transportation and power industries. Skilled in Electrical Engineering, Leadership, Test Automation and Manufacturing Design. Fluent in English with professional working proficiency in French. Strong engineering professional working towards a Bachelor of Technology – B.Tech focused in Power & Energy Engineering from McMaster University.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

RESEARCH ASSISTANT II

McMaster Automotive Resource Centre (MARC), January 2020 – Present

Undergraduate research assistant working in the battery testing lab.

- Developed an electrical safety training course, standard operating procedures and risk assessment documentation for students and researchers working on electrified transportation technology across the University
- Assembled, documented and prepared for field certification of a custom battery cycler
- Performed lithium cell characterization tests on varying chemistries and form factors

TEAM CAPTAIN

MAC Formula Electric, McMaster University, September 2017 – Present

Chief engineer and project manager responsible for the MAC Formula SAE Electric racing team. Lead development of the in-house designed accumulator and all subsequent systems necessary for delivering and controlling power to the four in-hub motors.

- Lead in development of the high voltage battery, PCB design with Altium, vehicle power simulations and battery state of charge
- Developed wiring assembly and schematic drawings and aided with harness manufacturing
- Introduced new project management mechanisms to improve team productivity
- Procured cash and product sponsorships from industry leaders and University departments

ELECTRICAL ENGINEERING TECHNOLOGIST

Erwin Hymer Group North America, Cambridge, July 2017 - August 2018

Principal electrical designer in multiple product development projects, including the Hymer Touring trailer and Roadtrek Transit Class B motorhome.

- Developed system schematics and wire harness drawings
- Coordinated with manufacturers to integrate subsystems into the primary coach control system
- Developed and executed test procedures for various research and development projects such as the in-house designed lithium batteries